Clara Andress

Senior Web Developer - Federal Occupational Health

Poulsbo, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Clara-Andress/27a849c372ebd59b

13+ years of professional experience on Microsoft SharePoint Portal technologies that includes Microsoft SharePoint Server 2010 and 2013, SharePoint Online, Microsoft Office SharePoint Server 2007 (MOSS 2007), SharePoint Portal Server 2003 and Windows SharePoint Services 3.0. Excellent problem solving skills, the "go-to" person for difficult issues. A team player with highly effective communication skills and the ability to operate independently.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer

Federal Occupational Health - Seattle, WA - 2004 to Present

Collaborated with clients, content owners, and power users to discuss the services SharePoint could provide to them, develop information architectures, and create robust solutions including custom code, and cross-platform mobile applications.

- ◆ Hands-on experience developing software applications following Agile/Scrum Software Development methodology in .NET Framework using ASP.NET, Web Services, SQL, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, and SharePoint APIs. Made use of Jira, Hipchat, Bitbucket, Git, and SourceTree to plan, collaborate, and develop applications and services.
- Designed sites, pages, lists, information architectures, InfoPath forms and workflows, workflow development, web part deployment, application integration, prototyping, reporting service integration and security architectures.
- Developed UI/functionality customizations using CSS, XSLT, JavaScript, JQuery, Master Pages customization, web services, DataViews, workflows, custom content types, data views, and Quest WebParts.
- Migrated medium SharePoint intranet portal farm from SharePoint 2007 environment to SharePoint 2010 and worked with Sharepoint 2010 to 2013 migration in test environment in order to prepare for future migration efforts.
- Created clinical portal using composites to facilitate seamless and secure interaction between branches.
- Developed custom wellness portal using Drupal 7 including, development of modules, views, and other elements via functional requirements, responsive theme/front-end development, custom module development, and web services.
- Implemented and maintained SharePoint Search Service, including configuration, definition of search scopes, indexing, and search crawls.
- Performed SharePoint and public web administration, including migration, maintenance, troubleshooting, and optimization. Designed, developed, deployed, and supported a medium SharePoint web farm.
- Mentored and trained the SharePoint team regarding development in the FOH SharePoint environment, best practices, secure coding, Section 508 Accessibility standards, and day to day operations and maintenance.
- Developed application documentation including troubleshooting guides and knowledgebase articles for helpdesk personnel and user manuals for business owners.
- Conducted training webinars and one-on-one trainings for end users.
- Performed user acceptance testing for developed applications including documentation and triage for bugs and enhancement requests.

Web Developer

- 2003 to 2007

Used SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) and Excel Services to develop custom scorecards for lines of business based on billing data datamart.

- Developed custom application for workflow mediation in ASP .NET for SharePoint.
- Developed custom Master Pages and CSS files for branding and to provide the portal with a consistent look and feel.
- Developed and provided support for SharePoint intranet site and public facing website
- Created custom SharePoint Lists, Document libraries, and custom Page Layouts.
- Performed SharePoint administrative responsibilities including creation of web applications, site collections, provisioning permissions, automation of day to day SharePoint backup and restores at site collection level.
- Installed, configured, and maintained SharePoint services on servers, including web front end, application, and database servers. Applied SharePoint patches and cumulative updates.
- Implemented Disaster recovery strategies for SharePoint, including replication of production servers.
- Performed SQL server maintenance activities including backup and restore, configuration of mirroring, and detaching/attaching of SQL databases.

Web Developer 2

Microsoft - Redmond, WA - 2003 to 2004

Developed branding, calendars, and custom lists using SharePoint 2003.

- Developed Windows XP operating system help files using HTML and CSS for the Windows International Team.
- Provided technical editing for help file content.

EDUCATION

Associate of Science in Information Technology in Information Technology

North Seattle community College - Seattle, WA